hey everybody welcome to this A2 English
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as I speak before we
start remember to download the listening
Time Podcast and if you want my
specialized training to help you improve
your listening then become a member at
remember you'll get my Advanced podcast
which will help you reach an advanced
level of listening okay today we're
going to talk about coffee for some of
you this might be a really important
topic that depends on how much you like
this drink let me first talk about my
relationship with coffee I'm not an
everyday coffee drinker and I don't need
coffee to feel awake or productive in
fact sometimes caffeine can be hard for
my body to handle if I drink too much of
it I might feel anxious or just bad
throughout the rest of the day so as you
can see I don't need coffee in my life
however on the other hand I really like
warm beverages it doesn't matter if it's
coffee tea hot chocolate apple cider or
any other hot drink I've always loved
these types of drinks so even though I
don't need coffee I actually do like
drinking it I often order coffee when I
eat breakfast at restaurants and I even
drink it at home sometimes but I know
many people who are dependent on coffee
and who couldn't imagine starting their
day without it okay let's talk about the
differences between coffee in different
parts of the world in the US it's really
common for people to drink a full cup of
coffee they fill up their mug and add
sweeteners like coffee creamer or sugar
I remember that my parents always had
different flavors of coffee creamer like
vanilla or hazelnut and they would add a
lot of this until their coffee was sweet
and often times they would refill their
mug and drink a second cup of coffee in
the morning however I know that in many
European countries this isn't normal in
some of these countries it's more common
to drink espresso shots these shots are
really small compared to the coffee that
many Americans drink they're usually
more concentrated too so the flavor is
much stronger honestly I've only had one
or two espresso shots in my whole life
so I don't have much experience with
this I prefer drinking full cups of
coffee because I like to savor the drink
this means that I like to drink it
slowly and enjoy it for a longer period
of time how about you do you prefer
drinking full cups of coffee or do you
like small espresso shots okay let's
talk a little bit about cafes in many
countries cafes are for more than just
coffee sure there are many people that
just order their coffee to go but a lot
of people spend time at coffee shops to
work hang out with friends read or just
relax a lot of cafes have good Wi-Fi
nice music and comfortable seating
personally I love working at cafes it's
a nice change from working here at my
house I feel a lot more inspired when
I'm in a different environment and when
I see other people around me where I
live it's common for people to bring
their laptop to the cafe and work while
they're drinking their coffee and I
think that coffee shops are also
comfortable places to just relax and
enjoy a nice drink okay that's all for
today remember to download the listening
Time Podcast and become a member at
patreon.com
listening time to receive my specialized
training which will help you understand
native speakers and if you want to reach
an advanced level of listening then
become a listening Time family member to
receive my Advanced podcast the link is
in the description below this video also
subscribe to the channel click on the
bell and follow us on Instagram I'll see
you next time